<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>willston.org</title><link>https://willston.org</link><description>willston.org RSS feed</description><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>End of Summer Update</title><description>&lt;p>Here is a long overdue update on what happened after the bootcamp. Thank you so much to everyone who helped make this happen!&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>All twelve students completed the curriculum taught during the week-long bootcamp, got to keep their laptops, and went to Busch Gardens&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Students were extremely engaged: one parent said, &amp;ldquo;they can&amp;rsquo;t stop talking about it at home&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Five students completed &lt;a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/learn/2022/responsive-web-design" target="_blank">freeCodeCamp&amp;#39;s (New) Responsive Web Design Certificate&lt;/a> (estimated 300 hours of work)
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Three of them received a brand new MacBook Air&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>All students received &lt;a href="https://willston.org/curriculum/glossary/#prizes" target="_blank">cash prizes&lt;/a> (at least $300)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>One student helped another, who hadn&amp;rsquo;t participated in the bootcamp, complete &lt;a href="https://willston.org/curriculum" target="_blank">Willston Web&amp;#39;s curriculum&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>One student created a &lt;a href="https://brandoniscoding381.github.io/portfolio/" target="_blank">public-facing website&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description><link>/end-of-summer-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/end-of-summer-update/</guid></item><item><title>Final Day Status Update</title><description>&lt;p>Today was the final day of Willston Web Coding Bootcamp as part of &lt;a href="https://www.comunidadva.org" target="_blank">Comunidad&lt;/a>&amp;rsquo;s
Rising Leaders Program. 12 students made significant progress on
&lt;a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/learn/2022/responsive-web-design/" target="_blank">freeCodeCamp&amp;#39;s (New) Responsive Web Design Course&lt;/a> throughout the week and
took home donated laptops today to continue working over the summer. Students
are incentivized to keep working, with prizes waiting for them upon completion
of major milestones. One student even stayed up until 2 am this morning to keep
working!&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/images/2022-06-17-1.jpg" alt="Bag of Hi-Chew next to Hershey's
kisses">
&lt;figcaption>Sometimes we needed a little extra motivation&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Here are a couple of photos from the week:&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/images/2022-06-17-2.jpg" alt="One student helps another by pointing to her screen">
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/images/2022-06-17-3.jpg" alt="One students writes out HTML on a whiteboard while the other watches">
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Students were inspired by the wonderful speakers who came throughout the week.
Here are a few takeaways from the lunchtime speakers:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Rebecca and Patrick of Comunidad kicked us off on Monday, and shared their
experiences in the tech industry. Rebecca learned web design over lockdown and
Patrick studied computer science in college and will be teaching CS at Gonzaga
College High School this fall.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Chris impressed upon us that &amp;ldquo;character counts&amp;rdquo; (pun intended?) and led
everyone through an example where he used Python web scraping to solve a real
life need. (I&amp;rsquo;ll be using what I learned from him to build a tool for students
to compare their progress with each other this summer.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Aidan, Ms. Maralee&amp;rsquo;s nephew, shared from the heart, making sure students
understood that it was ok and normal to struggle at times. He emphasized the
importance of perseverance and also provided practical college and career
advice.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dani, Jordi, Josie, Julia, and Tomi, came from MasterCard and seem to have
found a great work-life balance. We learned that internships during college
can really prepare you well for future employment.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Albert, Ian, Katie came from &lt;a href="https://www.brazen.com" target="_blank">Brazen&lt;/a> to share about jobs in information
technology and security. We also learned that a college degree isn&amp;rsquo;t always
necessary to find a job in the IT field, since certificates can vouch for your
competency.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Ricardo did an amazing job introducing speakers throughout the week and leading
the panel today!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This week was a huge win for everyone involved! We will provide an update later
in August when the program comes to an end. Thank you for believing in Willston
Web.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/images/2022-06-17-4.jpg" alt="Group photo">
&lt;/figure></description><link>/final-day/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/final-day/</guid></item><item><title>Day 1 Status Update</title><description>&lt;p>Today was the first day of the Willston Web Coding Bootcamp and it was a great
success! Thank you to Ms. Maralee, Patrick, Rebecca, Ricardo, and my mom for
arriving early to help set up. All 13 students we were expecting showed up and
were very interested in learning. They stayed on task and were productive with
their time. Many of them are eager to continue working and wanted to bring their
laptops home so they could keep going through curriculum. The prospect of a
premium laptop is quite the motivator! One student has limited English
proficiency, but was still able to follow along with brief explanations in
Spanish when needed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Students learned how to use a new operating system (&lt;a href="https://pop.system76.com" target="_blank">Pop!_OS&lt;/a>), laid out HTML
document structure with paper, and completed at least steps 1-6 of
&lt;a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/learn/2022/responsive-web-design/" target="_blank">freeCodeCamp&amp;#39;s (New) Responsive Web Design Certificate&lt;/a>, where they learned
about header and paragraph tags, comments, SEO (search engine optimization), and
indentation. Here is a &lt;a href="/curriculum/bootcamp/1">link to today&amp;#39;s lesson plan&lt;/a> and below are photos from
our first day:&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/images/2022-06-13-1.jpg" alt="Wilson looks to the board for instruction">
&lt;figcaption>Wilson looks to the board for instruction&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/images/2022-06-13-2.jpg" alt="Janet points out something to Juan">
&lt;figcaption>Janet points out something to Juan&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/images/2022-06-13-3.jpg" alt="Juan explains a concept to Janet">
&lt;figcaption>Juan explains a concept to Janet&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/images/2022-06-13-4.jpg" alt="Jonathan (student) works with Patrick">
&lt;figcaption>Patrick works with Jonathan (student), who is next to Mark&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/images/2022-06-13-5.jpg" alt="The team pauses for a picture after setting up for the day">
&lt;figcaption>The team pauses for a picture after setting up for the day&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure></description><link>/first-day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/first-day/</guid></item><item><title>Ready to Start the First Bootcamp</title><description>&lt;p>Tomorrow morning, 13 students will walk in the doors of the Willston
Multicultural Center to learn web development, hear from an amazing array of 9
or so guest speakers, and have the opportunity to take home a laptop. Thank you
to all of the people who are making this possible. We have raised over $5,000
and have received 10 laptops with an estimated value of ~$3,000. Wow! I simply
do not have words to express how grateful I am for the generosity shown to
(hopefully) make this project a success. Thank you to &lt;a href="https://comunidadva.org" target="_blank">Comunidad&lt;/a>; without our
partnership, we would not have a physical space for the bootcamp, students, or
the ability to receive donations. &lt;a href="https://restorationarlington.org" target="_blank">Restoration Anglican Church&lt;/a> has shown up in
ways I never could have imagined. They have provided tremendous support in
getting the word out about Willston Web. Most of our laptops, monetary
contributions, and speakers have come through members of Restoration. I could
not ask to be a part of a better church.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Below is a photo of the 13 computers physically cleaned, digitally wiped, and
ready for a new owner! We purchased a couple of additional laptops (with one
arriving today) since we ended up having more students than we anticipated (a
good thing!).&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="/images/2022-06-12-computers.jpg" alt="13 computers stacked up, ready for students">
&lt;figcaption>Computers ready for Monday&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll periodically be posting updates on the status of the bootcamp, so make sure
you&amp;rsquo;re subscribed! Feel free to share this with anyone who might also want to
hear about how the bootcamp is going. We are excited to meet our students!&lt;/p></description><link>/ready-to-start-first-bootcamp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ready-to-start-first-bootcamp/</guid></item><item><title>The Lenovo IdeaPad 1</title><description>&lt;p>Over the past number of years, Chromebooks have become quite popular, with &lt;a href="https://www.blog.google/outreach-initiatives/education/2020-chromebooks/" target="_blank">40
million currently used in education&lt;/a>. The three main reasons people use
Chromebooks are cost, simplicity, and it&amp;rsquo;s provided by their school. These are
all valid reasons for using a Chromebook, but I would like to break each one
down and provide an example of a comparable laptop that isn&amp;rsquo;t a Chromebook and
can better serve as a phenomenal device for someone looking to get into
programming.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="cost">Cost&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This reason why people purchase Chromebooks makes a lot of sense. They are a lot
cheaper than many other laptops available. For the vast majority of people, cost
determines is the most important factor when purchasing a computing device.
Google did a great job lowering the barrier to entry to computers. A decent
Chromebook can now be purchased for ~$100-250. Chrome OS can run on devices that
would have a hard time running Windows or cannot even run Windows because they
have an ARM processor. While ARM processors are really efficient, adoption has
not gotten nearly as close to that of x86_64 processors yet, so there is still a
lot of software that works well on on x86_64 processors, but not on ARM.
Luckily, there are x86_64 laptops that are in the same price range as
Chromebooks (hint: the Lenovo IdeaPad 1).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="simplicity">Simplicity&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Chrome OS is essentially a glorified web browser with the ability to save a few
files to the hard drive&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, which isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily a bad thing. This is all
some people —if you just require the ability to check email and visit a few
websites in an operating system, you don&amp;rsquo;t need anything more than Chrome OS;
however, programmers need a little more freedom with their operating system that
what Chrome OS provides. For users that are not so technically savvy, a
Chromebook that comes with Chrome OS pre-installed is really the only option as
Linux is still too difficult for the average person to install, but I urge those
who would like to get into programming to take the time to learn how to flash a
Linux distribution to USB stick and install a Linux themselves&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. The &lt;a href="https://getfedora.org/en/workstation/download/" target="_blank">Fedora
Media Writer&lt;/a> makes this super simple, but it&amp;rsquo;s not much more difficult to
download the &lt;a href="https://linuxmint.com/" target="_blank">Linux Mint&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://ubuntu.com/desktop" target="_blank">Ubuntu&lt;/a>, or any other Linux distribution&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code>.iso&lt;/code>
and flash the USB stick yourself using a tool like &lt;a href="https://balenaetcher.net/" target="_blank">Balena Etcher&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="school">School&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With strong Google Workspace integration, it is no surprise that many schools
opt for Chromebooks when providing laptops for students. When you are given a
computer from school, there is not much you can do, but be grateful that your
school system provided you with a laptop at all. Chromebooks, Chrome OS, and
Google Workspace are phenomenal for collaborating with others, turning in
assignments, and making presentations, but are not so optimized for programming.
If schools want to make it easy for their students to write real code, I urge
them to consider laptops and operating systems that are conducive to programming
(meaning you don&amp;rsquo;t have to jump through hoops to get a development environment
working). I understand that this isn&amp;rsquo;t always possible because schools have to
keep security top of mind and can&amp;rsquo;t really have students installing whatever
software they please. Unfortunately, this means that students with their own
personal computers are able to set up a development environment and start
programming, but those who are dependent on the school for computer access are
limited by the tools their school provides&lt;sup id="fnref:3">&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. There are no winners in this
situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-ideapad-1">The IdeaPad 1&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We were fortunate to receive the generous donation of two brand new &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Lenovo-IdeaPad-Processor-Graphics-81VU00D1US/dp/B09BG85LRV" target="_blank">14-inch
Lenovo IdeaPad 1 laptops&lt;/a>, which at time of writing, cost ~$245. These laptops
come with Windows installed, so if you are a Windows user, this is a great
Chromebook-priced Windows machine. For others, this laptop could be your entry
to Linux and programming. Linux works great on the IdeaPad 1–all necessary
drivers are in the Linux kernel, so everything including WiFi and the webcam
work out-of-the-box and it has a x86_64 processor, so virtually all Linux
software works on this machine. The two main downsides of this laptop are that
there are no USB-C ports and there is limited storage (64GB), but the storage is
comparable to Chromebooks and could be expanded with the MicroSD card slot. The
keyboard is one of the best I&amp;rsquo;ve used on a laptop and running GNOME 42 in Fedora
36 feels extremely snappy. There is very little to complain about.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My reason for writing this isn&amp;rsquo;t to say that Chromebooks are bad or shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be
purchased, but that there are arguably better options for people looking to
program on their new device. The Lenovo IdeaPad 1 is not the only one of its
kind either—it&amp;rsquo;s just an option. Do your own research before purchasing a new
laptop. I am really happy with this one and am excited to see what our students
think of these new machines!&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1">
&lt;p>Technically, most Chromebooks have eMMC, but &amp;ldquo;hard drive&amp;rdquo; gets the point
across better.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:2">
&lt;p>Yes, I know you can &lt;a href="https://sites.google.com/a/chromium.org/dev/chromium-os/chrome-os-systems-supporting-linux" target="_blank">install Linux on select Chromebooks&lt;/a>,
if you&amp;rsquo;re going to install Linux inside of Chrome OS, why not just install Linux
on the entire operating system. It&amp;rsquo;s less of a headache and if you purchase a
device with x86_64 architecture, you won&amp;rsquo;t run into software compatibility with
ARM-based systems.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:3">
&lt;p>At my school, my computer science teacher had to cancel an assignment
because not every student could install the &lt;code>pomegranate&lt;/code> library in Python.
Not every student that used a school computer had the same errors and it was
difficult to figure out what happened because the Windows Command Prompt was
blocked from opening.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/div></description><link>/ideapad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/ideapad/</guid></item><item><title>Making Fedora Linux Look a Little More Like Windows</title><description>&lt;p>There are a few simple modification that you can make to stock GNOME to make the
transition from Windows to Linux a little easier. They are pretty simple: adding
a couple of additional buttons to the window titlebar and combining the
application launcher and system tray to make the taskbar more similar to that
found in Windows. Below are screenshots of before and after the tweaks. Look
carefully for the aforementioned changes:&lt;/p>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img alt="Before Dash to Panel" src="/images/2022-05-25-before.png">
&lt;figcaption>Stock GNOME 42&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img alt="After Dash to Panel" src="/images/2022-05-25-after.png">
&lt;figcaption>After changes. Notice the additional buttons in the titlebar and
the addition of a Windows-like taskbar.&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>As you can see, the changes are subtle, but can make a Windows user feel a lot
more at home using the GNOME desktop environment. Here are the steps to
replicate these changes on Fedora:&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="update-all-packages">Update all packages&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;code>$ sudo dnf update&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="install-gnome-tweaks">Install GNOME Tweaks&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;code>$ sudo dnf install gnome-tweaks&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open GNOME Tweaks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Navigate to: Window Titlebars &amp;gt; Titlebar Buttons&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Turn the following settings on:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Maximize&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Minimize&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="install-dash-to-panel">Install Dash to Panel&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Visit the &lt;a href="https://extensions.gnome.org/extension/1160/dash-to-panel/" target="_blank">Dash to Panel&lt;/a> page&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Install the GNOME Shell integration by selecting &lt;code>Click here to install the browser extension&lt;/code> and following the subsequent instructions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Refresh the page&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Switch the toggle labeled &lt;code>OFF&lt;/code> to &lt;code>ON&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Select &lt;code>Install&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description><link>/gnome-like-windows/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/gnome-like-windows/</guid></item><item><title>Broadcom WiFi Driver Issues on Fedora Linux</title><description>&lt;p>Broadcom brand WiFi drivers are notorious for not working by default on Linux.
Every time I need to install drivers to make Broadcom WiFi cards work on Fedora
Linux, I have trouble finding up to date information, which is why I writing
down the steps here—both for future is reference and in case someone else runs
into the same issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="installing-broadcom-wifi-drivers-on-fedora-linux">Installing Broadcom WiFi Drivers on Fedora Linux&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Note: I used the following steps to install the &lt;code>BCM4352&lt;/code> WiFi driver on Fedora
36, but this should work for other Broadcom WiFi cards and versions of Fedora
Linux. Your mileage may vary.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Update packages: &lt;code>$ sudo dnf update&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://docs.fedoraproject.org/en-US/quick-docs/setup_rpmfusion/" target="_blank">Enable RPM Fusion repositories&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Make sure to install both free and nonfree repositories&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Install Broadcom WiFi drivers: &lt;code>$ sudo dnf install broadcom-wl&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Restart the computer: &lt;code>$ sudo reboot&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description><link>/fedora-broadcom/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/fedora-broadcom/</guid></item><item><title>About</title><description>&lt;style>
p > img {
width: 150px;
float: left;
margin-right: 30px;
margin-left: 0px;
margin-bottom: 20px;
}
h1 {
margin-bottom: 0;
}
h2 {
margin-top: 0;
}
h3 {
text-align: left;
}
h3:not(:first-of-type), img:not(:first-of-type) {
margin-top: 25px;
}
[@media](@media) only screen and (max-width: 600px) {
h3:not(:first-of-type), img:not(:first-of-type) {
margin-top: 50px;
}
}
&lt;/style>
&lt;h2 id="our-story">Our Story&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;img alt="quote" src="/images/quote.svg" width="80">&lt;br>"Can you teach me?"
&lt;br>
&lt;footer>&lt;i>– Ricardo Perez, co-founder and inspiration for Willston Web&lt;/i>&lt;/footer>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Willston Web was born of friendship: when expressing his frustration with the monotony of his current job sorting clothes in retail, Ricardo asked Jonathan, "Can you teach me [web development]?" upon hearing about Jonathan's work managing websites. Jonathan had been wondering how he could make web development more accessible and share skills he had developed at his science and technology focused high school, so he was elated to hear Ricardo desired to learn web development and thought that there might be others like him. Together, they are planning the Willston Web bootcamp. Along with increasing access to personal computers and inspiring students to pursue a career in programming, they want to foster a &lt;i>web&lt;/i> of students that learn together in a community effort.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="our-team">Our Team&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="ricardo-perez">Ricardo Perez&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/images/ricardo.jpg" alt="Ricardo picture">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Cofounder&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ricardo is a junior at Justice High School and the catalyst for inception of
Willston Web. He serves as a Rising Leader with &lt;a href="https://comunidadva.org" target="_blank">Comunidad&lt;/a> and is eager to
learn the basics of web development. He sees Willston Web as a great place to
learn how to &amp;ldquo;to make money in your space, at home, while you take care of your
brothers or sisters.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 style="margin-top: 100px">Jonathan Buchholz&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/images/jonathan.jpg" alt="Jonathan picture">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Cofounder&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jonathan is a junior at Thomas Jefferson High School for Science and Technology.
He has a strong background in computer science (Python and Java) from his time
at school and taught himself web development when school shut down in 2020,
which gave him the skills to work his first job. You can find out more about
Jonathan on &lt;a href="https://buchh.org" target="_blank">his website&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="catherine-buchholz">Catherine Buchholz&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/images/catherine.jpg" alt="Catherine picture">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Lead Designer&lt;/strong>&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Catherine is an 8th grader at Mary Ellen Henderson Middle School. She has an eye
for beautiful design and made with Willston Web logo. If you like our YouTube
thumbnails or are interested in learning more about her work, visit &lt;a href="https://catherinebuchholz.com" target="_blank">her website&lt;/a>!
She does commission pieces, but her work for Willston Web is pro
bono.&lt;/p></description><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid></item><item><title>Donate</title><description> &lt;header>
&lt;p>You can help us out in two ways:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://secure.squarespace.com/checkout/donate?donatePageId=62545ae65f741415ccb30a06&amp;ss_cvr=c9f1ff42-4c32-47a0-82a7-f943d0465c79%7C1649695405308%7C1649706858547%7C1649711851970%7C4&amp;ss_cvt=1649711851970&amp;websiteId=606e111c9bb1905684a7f967" target="_blank">&lt;b>Donate through Comunidad&lt;/b>&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://forms.gle/cR3RKn4DFWZrqDfNA" target="_blank">&lt;b>Donate a used laptop&lt;/b>&lt;/a>
&lt;/p>
&lt;/header>
&lt;p>Comunidad is a 501(c)(3), so giving through them is tax deductible.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="laptops">Laptops&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We are extremely grateful to have received the following computers so far
(estimated $3,250 value):&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 2013 15-inch Retina MacBook Pro (~$300 value) with the following specs:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2.4 GHz Intel Quad-Core Core i7 processor&lt;/li>
&lt;li>16 GB RAM&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Intel HD Graphics 4000 1536 MB graphics&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 2015 15-inch Retina MacBook Pro (~$600 value) with the following specs:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2.8 GHz Intel Quad-Core Core i7 processor&lt;/li>
&lt;li>16 GB RAM&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Intel Iris Pro 1536 MB graphics&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 2015 15-inch Retina MacBook Pro (~600 value) with the following specs:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2.8 GHz Intel Quad-Core Core i7 processor&lt;/li>
&lt;li>16 GB RAM&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Intel Iris Pro graphics&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 2015 13-inch Retina MacBook Pro (~$500 value) with the following specs:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2.7 GHz Intel Quad-Core i5 processor&lt;/li>
&lt;li>8 GB RAM&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Intel Iris Graphics&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 2015 Dell Latitude E5450 (~$250 value) with the following specs:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2.3 GHz Quad-Core Intel i5 processor&lt;/li>
&lt;li>8 GB RAM&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Intel Mesa HD graphics&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 2017 HP Prodesk 400 G3 Desktop Mini (~$150 value) with the following specs:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>3.3 GHz Intel Quad-Core i5 graphics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>8 GB RAM&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Intel HD Graphics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>500 GB storage&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 2014 Lenovo IdeaPad U430 Touch (~$150 value) with the following specs:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1.7 GHz Intel Quad-Core i5 processor&lt;/li>
&lt;li>8 GB&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Intel Mesa HD graphics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>500 GB storage&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 14-inch Lenovo IdeaPad 1 laptops (~$300 value) with the following specs:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1.1 GHz Intel Celeron processor&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 GB RAM&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Intel UHD graphics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>64 GB storage&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 2012 13-inch MacBook Pro (~$100 value)
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2.5 GHz Intel Quad-Core i5 processor&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 GB RAM&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Mesa Intel HD graphics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>500 GB storage&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description><link>/donate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/donate/</guid></item><item><title>Press</title><description>&lt;p>Here are places where Willston Web has been mentioned on other websites:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Comunidad&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://www.comunidadva.org/willstonweb" target="_blank">page on Willston Web&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://restorationarlington.org/2022/05/rectors-update-2-ways-to-invest-in-our-youth/" target="_blank">Restoration Arlington&amp;#39;s Rector&amp;#39;s Update&lt;/a> on May 18, 2022&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description><link>/press/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/press/</guid></item><item><title>Thanks for subscribing!</title><description>&lt;!-- You should receive an email from us in your inbox momentarily asking you to
confirm your email. All you need to do is click the link to make sure you get
emails from us in the future. Check your junk folder if you don't see anything
from us. Please add [jonathan@willston.org](mailto:jonathan@willston.org) to
your contacts to ensure our emails won't end up in your junk folder. -->
&lt;p>Thanks for signing up for updates! Please add
&lt;a href="mailto:jonathan@willston.org">jonathan@willston.org&lt;/a> to your contacts to ensure
our emails won&amp;rsquo;t end up in your junk folder.&lt;/p></description><link>/subscribed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/subscribed/</guid></item><item><title>Your email is confirmed!</title><description>&lt;p>Thanks for confirming your email. You&amp;rsquo;ll get updates from us from now on. Please
add &lt;a href="mailto:jonathan@willston.org">jonathan@willston.org&lt;/a> to your contacts to
ensure our emails won&amp;rsquo;t end up in your junk folder.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Share &lt;a href="https://willston.org" target="_blank">willston.org&lt;/a> with a friend if you&amp;rsquo;re so inclined!&lt;/p></description><link>/confirmed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/confirmed/</guid></item></channel></rss>